Samuel Tracy

Phone: (916) 764-9002 Email: stracy@g.harvard.edu Web: https://seasamgo.github.io

Ph.D. candidate in Biostatistics at Harvard University focusing on methods for failure time data and single-cell sequencing data. In particular: developing and adapting sampling techniques, optimization theory, adjustments for missingness, clustering methods, and dimensionality reduction. My advisor is Dr. Guo-Cheng Yuan. I am also an advocate for open-source development, reproducible research and diversity in STEM.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Biostatistics	Harvard University	2019^{1}
M.A. Biostatistics	Harvard University	2016
B.S. Applied Mathematics, magna cum laude	UC San Diego	2014

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Consultant	09/2017 – present

Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health, Boston, MA Biostatistics Student Consulting Center

Student Intern 03/2013 – 06/2013

Clinical & Translational Research Institute, San Diego, CA Clinical data analysis under Dr. Ronghui Xu and James Proudfoot

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant 01/2016 – present

Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health, Boston, MA

BST 210 Applied Regression Analysis

BST 226 Applied Longitudinal Analysis

Instructor and Administrator 01/2015 - 08/2017

StatStart: a High School Summer Program in Biostatistics, Boston, MA

Statistical computing with the programming language R

Teaching Assistant 09/2013 – 06/2014

UC San Diego, San Diego, CA MATH 10ABC Calculus Series

Academic Liaison 01/2013 – 03/2013

Fallbrook High School, Fallbrook, CA

Through the UC San Diego Educational Studies Department, San Diego, CA

_

¹ anticipated

PUBLICATIONS

Talbot, O., Ocampo, A., Tracy, S., Mosesso, K., Rahman, A., and Pagano, M. (2016). StatStart 2015. *ASA: The Statistics Teacher Network*, 87: 4-8.

IN PROGRESS

Chen, T., Tracy, S., Uno, H. OptBand: optimal confidence bands for functions to characterize time-to-event distributions.

Tracy, S., Dries, R., Yuan, G.C. A nonparametric method to impute dropout in single-cell RNA-sequencing data.

Tracy, S., Yuan, G.C. A selection method for cell trajectory models applied to single-cell RNA-sequencing data.

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Software – R, MATLAB, Stata, Java, C++, Python

Interests – tumor evolution and heterogeneity, systems architecture, cyber security

SOFTWARE

Co-creator and maintainer of the R package *optband* (on CRAN and GitHub), which contains methods for minimal-area simultaneous confidence bands applicable to failure-time data.

SELECTED INVOLVEMENT

Graduate Student Council, Department Representative	09/2015 - 08/2017
Roxbury Prep Tutoring, Co-director	09/2016 - 05/2017
Roxbury Prep Tutoring, Coordinator	09/2015 - 05/2016
Student Conduct Code Committee, Student Representative	01/2014 - 06/2014
Global Water Brigades, Honduras Brigade Member	01/2014 - 03/2014

REFERENCES

Yuan, Guo-Cheng

Associate Professor, Department of Biostatistics, Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health Address: 360 Longwood Ave, Room 1060, Boston, MA 02215

Tel: (617) 582-8532 Email: gcyuan@jimmy.harvard.edu

Xu, Ronghui

Professor, Department of Mathematics, University of California, San Diego

Address: 9500 Gilman Drive #0112, La Jolla, CA 92093

Tel: (858) 534-6380 Email: rxu@ucsd.edu